[
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If it takes 900 Btus [B-T-USE] of fuel to produce a gallon of hot water and you take a 10 minute shower using 2 gallons of hot water per minute, how many Btus of fuel were used in the shower?",
        "Answer": "18,000"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is closest to the maximum horsepower a healthy person can briefly generate?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "0.25",
            "X": "0.5",
            "Y": "1",
            "Z": "2"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Chlorophyll undergoes which of the following types of reaction when it is activated by light?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Reduction",
            "X": "Oxidation",
            "Y": "Hydrolysis [hy-DROL-uh-sis]",
            "Z": "Phosphorylation [FOS-fer-uh-lay-shuhn]"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Approximately how many pounds of coal are required to light a 100 watt light bulb for one year?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "325",
            "X": "450",
            "Y": "575",
            "Z": "700"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Methane\u2122s influence on global warming is approximately how many times that of carbon dioxide?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1/2",
            "X": "10",
            "Y": "20",
            "Z": "40"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "About how many pounds of carbon dioxide are generated by burning 6 pounds of pure carbon?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "22",
            "X": "32",
            "Y": "42",
            "Z": "52"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following correctly matches the major energy source and fuel for most stars?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Nuclear fission and hydrogen",
            "X": "Nuclear fission and helium",
            "Y": "Nuclear fusion and hydrogen",
            "Z": "Nuclear fusion and helium"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "By number, identify all of the following three statements that correctly indicate advantages of the high energy phosphate system: 1) It produces energy at a slow rate but for a long duration; 2) Its rate of recovery is relatively rapid; 3) It can produce large amounts of energy in a short amount of time.",
        "Answer": "2 AND 3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "About how many Btus does a therm of natural gas have?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "100,000",
            "X": "1 million",
            "Y": "10 million",
            "Z": "100 million"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Given h = 6.62 x10-34  joule seconds and providing your answer in scientific notation, calculate the number of photons in 6.62 joules of radiation energy of frequency 1012 hertz.",
        "Answer": "1 X 1022"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "When comparing the amount of food energy taken in to the energy available to do work, about how efficient is a human?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "15%",
            "X": "25%",
            "Y": "35%",
            "Z": "45%"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If a gallon of gasoline costs $3.50, how much will you save each year if you have a car getting 40 miles per gallon compared to a car getting 20 miles per gallon if you drive 20,000 miles per year?",
        "Answer": "$1,750"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "How many Btus are required to raise 3 pounds of water from 60\u00b0 Fahrenheit to 130\u00b0 Fahrenheit?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "63",
            "X": "70",
            "Y": "210",
            "Z": "390"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If my current annual heating bill is $900 and my old furnace has an efficiency rating of 75%, which of the following best approximates my new bill if I install a 95% efficient furnace?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "$675",
            "X": "$690",
            "Y": "$710",
            "Z": "$840"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Approximately how many square miles of photovoltaic panels would be required to provide power for the entire U.S. during daylight hours?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "2,500",
            "X": "10,000",
            "Y": "40,000",
            "Z": "100,000"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "At  120 volts, which of the following is the approximate amperage through a circuit that consists of resistors of 5 ohms, 10 ohms, and 20 ohms in series, followed by the same resistors in parallel?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "3.16",
            "X": "3.42",
            "Y": "4.66",
            "Z": "35"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Roof overhangs used to shade windows, walls, and doors from direct solar radiation in order to cut down on cooling costs are an example of what kind of home energy design?",
        "Answer": "PASSIVE SOLAR"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In megawatts, providing your answer to the nearest tenth, how much power is generated from a hydroelectric facility that has a head of 50 meters, a flow rate of 5,000 liters per second, and a coefficient of efficiency of 0.6?",
        "Answer": "1.5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If a utility uses a true real time pricing rate structure, a residential customer could reduce consumption during the times of peak demand by upgrading all but which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Lighting",
            "X": "Heating",
            "Y": "Air conditioning",
            "Z": "Water heating"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What process is represented by the following: (Coal) + O2 + H2O 2 + CO?",
        "Answer": "COAL GASIFICATION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following provides the highest average efficiency increase in vehicle engines?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Variable valve timing and lift",
            "X": "Cylinder deactivation",
            "Y": "Integrated starter/generator systems",
            "Z": "Direct fuel injection with turbocharging or supercharging"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Rank the following four locations in terms of evaporative cooling effectiveness, from worst to best: 1) Portland, Oregon; 2) New York City, New York; 3) Tucson, Arizona; 4) Boise, Idaho.",
        "Answer": "1, 2, 4, 3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following statements is NOT true about the \ufb01snowflake diverter\ufb02 at Princeton Plasma Physics Laboratory?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It is used in fusion research",
            "X": "It increases the impurity contamination level of the main plasma",
            "Y": "Its name is derived from the appearance of its magnetic field lines",
            "Z": "It reduces the interaction between hot plasma and the cold walls surrounding it"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "By number, rank the following four choices by their R-value from least to greatest: 1) 4-inch thick brick, 2) Half-inch thick drywall, 3) One eighth inch thick flat glass, 4) 3.5 inch thick stagnant air space.",
        "Answer": "4, 2, 3, 1"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the term for the rate at which an electricity generator steadily changes its output to meet electricity demand?",
        "Answer": "RAMP RATE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "By number, identify all of the following four statements regarding energy systems that are true: 1) Aerobic and anaerobic distinction is made depending on whether carbon dioxide is produced in the production of energy; 2) Both aerobic and anaerobic energy systems use substrate phosphorylation to synthesize ATP; 3) Energy systems differ from each other with respect to the rate and the duration of energy production; 4) Lactic acid is produced during energy production by the high energy phosphate system.",
        "Answer": "2 AND 3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "After refining a barrel of oil, which of the following fuel fractions constitutes the largest share?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Gasoline",
            "X": "Diesel",
            "Y": "Butane",
            "Z": "Jet fuel"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Efficiency of concentrated solar power systems at certain concentrations of light are a function of thermal radiation properties and what other factor?",
        "Answer": "CARNOT'S PRINCIPLE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How much power in watts is consumed by a device with a resistance of 15 ohms at a current of 3 amperes?",
        "Answer": "135"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following greenhouse gases stays the longest in the atmosphere?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Nitrous oxide",
            "X": "Carbon dioxide",
            "Y": "Sulfur hexafluoride",
            "Z": "Methane"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following types of battery has the highest energy density?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Lithium-ion",
            "X": "Lead-acid",
            "Y": "Nickel-cadmium",
            "Z": "Metal hydride"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "By number, rank the following four electricity generating resources in terms of total fixed and variable cost of operation and maintenance per megawatt-hour from least to greatest: 1) nuclear, 2) hydropower, 3) conventional coal, 4) natural gas.",
        "Answer": "2, 1, 3, 4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Besides length, what is the primary characteristic that determines line losses in electricity transmission?",
        "Answer": "FREQUENCY"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Many battery chargers can consume 5 times the amount of power in the battery itself, even when not actively charging a product. Assuming this is true and the charger is plugged in constantly, what is the expected annual consumption in kilowatt-hours of a battery charger for a 5 watt battery, rounded to one significant figure?",
        "Answer": "200"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Members of which of the following series, such as plutonium, are generally used in the nuclear energy field?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "C",
            "X": "F",
            "Y": "J",
            "Z": "K"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If a single 5 megawatt wind turbine generates 17,000 megawatt-hours of electricity annually, to the nearest 10%, what is its capacity factor?",
        "Answer": "40%"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following substances contains the most Btus per pound?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Peat",
            "X": "Gasoline",
            "Y": "Hydrogen",
            "Z": "Charcoal"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Approximately how much power in watts is consumed by, respectively,  five 120 volt incandescent light bulbs consuming 0.5 amperes each compared to five compact fluorescent lamp bulbs producing the equivalent lumens?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "120 versus 25",
            "X": "300 versus 65",
            "Y": "330 versus 220",
            "Z": "600 versus 300"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If a water heater uses 20 cubic feet of natural gas in 30 minutes and natural gas contains 1,000 Btus [B-T-USE] per cubic foot, what is the hourly input rating of the water heater in Btu per hour?",
        "Answer": "40,000"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What physical property is used to rate building insulation?",
        "Answer": "THERMAL RESISTANCE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is considered a zero marginal cost generator?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Nuclear",
            "X": "Wind",
            "Y": "Biomass",
            "Z": "Geothermal"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How much power in watts is consumed by a motor running at 440 volts and drawing 6.6 amperes?",
        "Answer": "2904"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many kilowatt-hours do you use annually if you have a 14 watt light bulb operating for 2,000 hours per year?",
        "Answer": "28"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Modern smart grid technology predominantly improves which of the following components of the electricity system?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Transmission and distribution",
            "X": "Fuel extraction",
            "Y": "Renewable energy generation",
            "Z": "Fossil fuel energy generation"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Kirchhoff's second law states that the directed sum of the voltage around any closed circuit is equal to what?",
        "Answer": "ZERO"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If a 20 watt computer monitor is left on 5,000 hours per year, how much does it cost to operate per year if a kilowatt-hour costs $0.15?",
        "Answer": "$15"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If a 1.5 megawatt turbine were to operate at its annual average all the time, about how many homes could it fully supply?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "3",
            "X": "100",
            "Y": "330",
            "Z": "550"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If you are driving 60 miles per hour and your car gets 30 miles per gallon, how many Btus [B-T-USE] of energy are you using per hour if gas contains 125,000 Btus per gallon?",
        "Answer": "250,000"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "To the nearest 10%, what is the approximate efficiency of commercially available high performance solar cells?",
        "Answer": "20%"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If a solar panel produces 200 watts of power, the energy is used to charge a battery with 80% efficiency, and the battery discharges with 80% efficiency, what percentage of the power is lost in the storage process?",
        "Answer": "36%"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In which of the following sets of three states is most U.S. oil shale located?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Utah, Montana, and Idaho",
            "X": "Colorado, Nevada, and New Mexico",
            "Y": "Colorado, Utah, and Wyoming",
            "Z": "Montana, Colorado, and Utah"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If a million people leave their cell phone chargers plugged in unnecessarily for 16 hours per day and each charger consumes 1 watt when not in use, providing your answer to the nearest million, how many kilowatt-hours are consumed per year while the chargers are plugged in but not charging?",
        "Answer": "6,000,000"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Who is generally credited with defining the term horsepower?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Thomas Edison",
            "X": "James Watt",
            "Y": "Michael Faraday",
            "Z": "Samuel Clinton"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The half life of radium is 1600 years. What fraction of the original quantity of radium has decayed after 9600 years?",
        "Answer": "63/64"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the typical electrical efficiency of a large energy-efficient electric motor?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "74%",
            "X": "89%",
            "Y": "94%",
            "Z": "99%"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following has the most kinetic energy?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "A 1 kilogram mass moving at 10 meters per second",
            "X": "A 2 kilogram mass moving at 7 meters per second",
            "Y": "A 0.5 kilogram mass moving at 14 meters per second",
            "Z": "A 0.25 kilogram mass moving at 18 meters per second"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT an advantage of using ethanol over gasoline for internal combustion engines?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "High octane rating",
            "X": "High thermal efficiency",
            "Y": "High compression rating",
            "Z": "High energy density"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following are the two primary products of combustion of methane gas in increasing order of molar amount?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Water vapor and carbon dioxide",
            "X": "Carbon monoxide and water vapor",
            "Y": "Carbon dioxide and water vapor",
            "Z": "Carbon monoxide and carbon dioxide"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the immediate use of glucose produced by photosynthesis?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "To capture light",
            "X": "To form fats and lipids",
            "Y": "To be consumed by heterotrophs",
            "Z": "An energy source for cellular respiration"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following elements has the greatest number of stable isotopes?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Lead",
            "X": "Plutonium",
            "Y": "Uranium",
            "Z": "Hydrogen"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following sources of energy produces radioactive waste?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Hydrogen",
            "X": "Geothermal",
            "Y": "Coal",
            "Z": "Oil"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A motor consumes 21 kilowatts at 90% efficiency. Which of the following is closest to the difference in operating costs over 20 years for this motor versus a 95% efficient motor, assuming that the motors are running constantly and that electricity costs $0.10 per kilowatt-hour.",
        "Options": {
            "W": "$5,000",
            "X": "$20,000",
            "Y": "$27,000",
            "Z": "$30,000"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Despite the heat produced from hydrothermal vents on the ocean floor, with temperatures reaching up to 400\u00b0 Celsius, the surrounding water does not boil. Why not?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The surrounding water is too cold",
            "X": "There is too much pressure at that depth",
            "Y": "The salt concentration is too high",
            "Z": "There is a low concentration of oxygen"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Approximately how many horsepower are generated by a horse pulling with a force of 180 pounds and turning a 24 foot diameter wheel 72 times in one hour?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1/2",
            "X": "3/4",
            "Y": "1",
            "Z": "5/4"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Photosynthesis accounts for the fixation of about 200 billion tons of carbon. Approximately which of the following percentages of this carbon is fixed by marine plankton alone?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "8%",
            "X": "24%",
            "Y": "40%",
            "Z": "65%"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Rank the four following forms of coal in order of energy per pound from least to greatest: 1) bituminous [by-TOO-muh-nuhs], 2) anthracite [AN-thruh-syt], 3) lignite, 4) sub-bituminous.",
        "Answer": "3, 4, 1, 2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following sectors consumes the most energy in the US?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Motor vehicle transportation",
            "X": "Commercial and residential buildings",
            "Y": "Air travel",
            "Z": "Electronics"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "On a per gram basis, why do carbohydrates contain less energy than hydrocarbons?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Carbohydrates contain oxygen and hydrocarbons do not",
            "X": "Carbohydrates cannot be burned and hydrocarbons can",
            "Y": "Hydrocarbons come from fossilized animals and plants but carbohydrates come from live or recently dead plants and animals",
            "Z": "Carbohydrates can be eaten but hydrocarbons cannot"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "On average, which of the following consumes the most electricity in an office building?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Space heating",
            "X": "Air cooling",
            "Y": "Lighting",
            "Z": "Office equipment"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT a way of storing energy?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Pumping water into a water tower on a hill",
            "X": "Dynamic braking on a diesel-electric locomotive",
            "Y": "Formation of NADPH in photosynthesis",
            "Z": "Storing molten salt"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "About how many tons of coal is required to produce the same amount of electricity produced by a typical power plant in one year?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "250,000",
            "X": "500,000",
            "Y": "1 million",
            "Z": "4 million"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "By number, rank the following four choices in order of increasing potential to impact climate change in the next 20 years: 1) C",
        "Answer": "1) CF"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the term for the system of power generation in which solar energy is converted to heat that drives a steam turbine?",
        "Answer": "CONCENTRATED SOLAR POWER"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "By number, rank the following four electricity generating resources in terms of capital cost per megawatt-hour from least to greatest: 1) hydropower, 2) nuclear, 3) conventional coal, 4) natural gas.",
        "Answer": "4, 3, 1, 2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "An air compressor is about 20% efficient in converting electricity to compressed air. Where does the majority of the remaining 80% of the electricity go?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It doesn't go anywhere, it stays in the motor",
            "X": "It turns into thermal energy",
            "Y": "It turns into sound",
            "Z": "It turns into vibration"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "As more zero variable cost generators are added to an electric power market, how would you expect the average cost of power in the entire market to change?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It would increase",
            "X": "It would decrease",
            "Y": "There would be no change",
            "Z": "It would fluctuate"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which trophic level has the most energy?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Consumers",
            "X": "Decomposers",
            "Y": "Producers",
            "Z": "Scavengers"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which is the approximate percentage of energy transfer from one trophic level to the next?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "10%",
            "X": "50%",
            "Y": "75%",
            "Z": "100%"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If a 250 acre farm were leased for wind development with income of $50 per acre per year, how much income would be produced each year?",
        "Answer": "$12,500"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Wind energy is the conversion of wind power into electricity, using wind turbines. Which of the following statements is true about wind energy systems?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Wind turbines convert kinetic energy from the wind",
            "X": "Wind farms have to be located on unoccupied pieces of land",
            "Y": "Wind energy systems have high impact on air emissions",
            "Z": "Construction costs for wind-powered generators are minimal"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A kilowatt-hour is a unit of:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Charge",
            "X": "Power",
            "Y": "Energy",
            "Z": "Electric potential"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the Gibbs free energy, in joules, of chlorine gas formation?",
        "Answer": "0"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In an electrolytic cell, what is the sign of the charge associated with the anode?",
        "Answer": "POSITIVE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following has NOT been shown to be a practical use of electrolytic cells?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Recovering pure metal from alloys",
            "X": "Electrolysis",
            "Y": "Plating of one metal with another",
            "Z": "Manufacturing of sodium hydroxide"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The human brain contains as many as 100 billion neurons. The neurons communicate with each other through electrochemical signals. Which of the following is NOT true?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Each neuron can connect to at least 1,000 other neurons",
            "X": "Neurons have a short life span",
            "Y": "Brain signals involve less than one-tenth the voltage of an ordinary flashlight battery",
            "Z": "Some messages pass through the nervous system more quickly than others"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Brain computer interfaces can measure minute differences in the voltage between neurons, amplify and filter the signal, and then a computer interprets it. All of the following are current applications of brain computer interfaces, except:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Controlling a computer cursor via mental commands",
            "X": "Interpreting brain signals for movement for someone who can\u00d5t physically move",
            "Y": "Providing a communication link for people who suffer from \u00d2locked in\u00d3 syndrome",
            "Z": "Repairing damaged neurons"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Hydrogen fuel cells use hydrogen to generate energy. Which of the following is true about hydrogen fuel cells?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Fuel cells are similar to batteries and store hydrogen, which is an energy source by itself",
            "X": "Fuel cells extract the hydrogen from other compounds in nature",
            "Y": "Fuel cells dissolve water into hydrogen, creating oxygen and energy",
            "Z": "Fuel cells convert chemical energy in hydrogen into electrical energy by combining hydrogen gas with oxygen from the air to produce water and energy"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If you were to use hydrogen fuel cells in spacecraft, what kind of fuel cell type would you most likely prefer?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Phosphoric acid",
            "X": "Molten carbonate",
            "Y": "Solid oxide",
            "Z": "Alkaline"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Which law of thermodynamics could be stated as: energy tends to distribute itself among the greatest number of particles possible?",
        "Answer": "2ND"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "When the same amount of energy is applied to 1-gram portions of water, ethanol, copper and iron, for which one does the temperature increase the least?",
        "Answer": "WATER  ________________________________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Wind can be harnessed to generate electricity via turbines. Which of the following is the greatest challenge to widespread use of wind for electricity?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Wind turbines are huge, expensive, and not particularly aesthetic",
            "X": "Wind has major negative ecological and environmental effects",
            "Y": "Suitable locations for wind farms with sufficiently constant and fast winds are limited",
            "Z": "Wind farms lead to significant loss of agricultural lands"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Identical wind turbines are put in four locations: sea level, 5,000 feet, 10,000 feet, and 14,000 feet.  Assuming the same wind speed, which turbine will produce the most energy?",
        "Answer": "SEA LEVEL"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "How is geothermal power produced?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Heat energy is extracted from high temperature lava after eruptions",
            "X": "Water from extremely hot springs is circulated in pipes in nearby homes for heating",
            "Y": "Hot dry volcanic rocks are extracted from deep underground and processed in place at a geothermal plant",
            "Z": "Mile-or-more-deep wells are drilled into underground reservoirs to tap steam and very hot water that drive turbines"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In order to replenish the supply of steam at the geothermal plant called The Geysers, which of the following does an underground pipeline deliver?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Wastewater",
            "X": "River water",
            "Y": "Ocean water",
            "Z": "Rain water"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the term used to describe the total amount of energy used in the production of a product, including raw material extraction, manufacture, transportation, assembly, and all other aspects of production?",
        "Answer": "EMBODIED ENERGY"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In 2009, demand for small wind systems for residential and small business use grew 15%, adding 20 megawatts of wind-generating capacity. What was the approximate capacity of small wind systems in 2008 in megawatts?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "17",
            "X": "35",
            "Y": "115",
            "Z": "133"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "During oxidative phosphorylation, the proton gradient is used to drive which enzyme?",
        "Answer": "ATP SYNTHASE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What is the approximate Gibbs free energy change per mole associated with oxidation of glucose?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "-3000 kilojoules",
            "X": "-3000 joules",
            "Y": "3000 joules Z ) 3000 kilojoules"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "An engine yields 100 watts of power for every 1000 watts received. What is the efficiency of the engine?",
        "Answer": "10%"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Using 750 watts per horsepower, if a 120 horsepower engine ran for 10 hours, how much energy, in kilowatt hours, would it consume? Provide your answer to the nearest integer.",
        "Answer": "900  ________________________________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A strong oxidizing agent would show which of the following characteristics?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "A large, positive reduction potential",
            "X": "A large, positive oxidation potential",
            "Y": "A small, positive reduction potential",
            "Z": "A small, positive oxidation potential"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the strongest reducing agent yielding the most ATP per molecule during oxidative phosphorylation?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "FADH2",
            "X": "FAD+",
            "Y": "NADH",
            "Z": "NAD+"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "One component of a solar energy system is the charge controller. Its function is to:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Provide electrical protection to the system",
            "X": "Regulate the amount of power that goes into energy storage for later use",
            "Y": "Dissipate excess energy",
            "Z": "Store the energy for later use"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How much heat in kilocalories does it take to heat 10 kilograms of bathwater from 10\u00a1 Celsius to 20\u00a1 Celsius?",
        "Answer": "100"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following principles is at work in hybrid cars?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Recapture some of car\u00d5s kinetic energy and use it to go faster",
            "X": "Recapture some of the car\u00d5s kinetic energy and use it for better fuel economy",
            "Y": "Recapture some of the car\u00d5s kinetic energy to synthesize gasoline",
            "Z": "Recapture engine heat and convert it to more kinetic energy for the car"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If a force of 10 newtons raises a mass 1.0 meters in 1.0 seconds, then what is the power in watts?",
        "Answer": "10  ________________________________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "When a 10 kilogram object is lifted 10 meters, in a gravitational field of 9.8 meters per second squared, what is the change in potential energy of the object in joules?",
        "Answer": "980"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Taking g as 10 meters per second squared and assuming there is no friction, at about what height in meters must a 100 kilogram roller coaster start from rest in order to achieve a speed of 100 meters per second at the bottom?",
        "Answer": "500  ________________________________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Why is riding a bicycle on a well-maintained road more energy efficient than walking or running?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Bipedal motion is highly inefficient",
            "X": "The coefficient of sliding friction between tires and the ground is less than that between shoes and the ground",
            "Y": "Gravity does very little work on a bicyclist relative to a walker or runner",
            "Z": "Bicycling requires more calories than walking"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "When a ball of mass m is launched vertically to a height h and returns to its original starting point of launch, what is the value of its change in gravitational potential energy?",
        "Answer": "0  ________________________________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "On a football team, there is a defensive lineman who weighs 350 pounds and can run at 10 miles per hour. On the same team, the wide receiver weighs 175 pounds and can run 20 miles per hour. At top speed, which player has more kinetic energy?",
        "Answer": "WIDE RECEIVER"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A race car initially moving with a velocity of 50 meters per second produces a skid mark on the road while braking. Using g as 10 meters per second squared, and providing your answer to the nearest integer, how long is the skid mark in meters if the coefficient of kinetic friction is 1.0?",
        "Answer": "125   ________________________________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "An electric vehicle has two stages. If the first stage, the battery, has an efficiency of 90% and the second stage, the inverter, has an efficiency of 80%, calculate the approximate overall efficiency of the vehicle.",
        "Options": {
            "W": "56%",
            "X": "72%",
            "Y": "89%",
            "Z": "113%"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How much work in joules is done by friction on a sled weighing 100 newtons during a 10 meter displacement? The coefficient of sliding friction is 0.1.",
        "Answer": "100"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Which type of crude oil is most desired, due to its low sulfur content and higher proportion of carbon chains that can be directed into the liquid fuel product?",
        "Answer": "LIGHT SWEET"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the most common sulfur compound that occurs naturally in natural gas.",
        "Answer": "HYDROGEN SULFIDE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Methane is emitted from a variety of anthropogenic and natural sources. The largest human-related source of methane emissions comes from enteric fermentation. At which of the following locations would you most likely find an example of enteric fermentation?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Petroleum system",
            "X": "Coal mine",
            "Y": "Landfill",
            "Z": "Cattle ranch"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Earth\u00d5s core is kept hot by the radioactive decay of several radioactive substances, including Uranium-235 and 238; name the other two heat-producing isotopes which are also significant contributors to the radioactive heat production of the Earth.",
        "Answer": "POTASSIUM-40 AND THORIUM-232"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What kind of potential energy is stored in the reservoir behind a dam?",
        "Answer": "GRAVITATIONAL"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT a significant limitation to the further development of U.S. hydropower?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Availability of sites for new large hydro facilities",
            "X": "Regulatory requirements",
            "Y": "Maintenance costs",
            "Z": "Environmental concerns"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following devices stores electrical energy in chemical form in order to release it slowly through a circuit?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Inductor",
            "X": "Resistor",
            "Y": "Capacitor",
            "Z": "Battery"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following types of battery is most commonly used in automobiles?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Lithium-ion (read as: LI-thee-uhm)",
            "X": "Nickel Cadmium",
            "Y": "Lead-acid",
            "Z": "Zinc chloride"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is a renewable resource?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Diamonds",
            "X": "Wood",
            "Y": "Coal",
            "Z": "Propane"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following choices describes one reason why the greenhouse effect is important?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It warms the Earth to a temperature necessary for life on Earth",
            "X": "It allows solar radiation to escape, preventing extreme radiation",
            "Y": "It cools the Earth to a temperature necessary for life on Earth",
            "Z": "It creates nitrogen for Earth\u00d5s atmosphere"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What is the challenge with regard to wind energy and transmission line capacity?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Not enough transmission lines connect cities to the windiest parts of the country",
            "X": "Transmission lines only have the capacity to transfer wind energy from small turbines",
            "Y": "Transmission lines must be buried",
            "Z": "We have more transmission lines than our power plants can currently support"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A wind energy system first converts the kinetic energy of the wind into what type of energy?",
        "Answer": "MECHANICAL"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Roberto lives in Florida. Which of the following is NOT a way that he could use less energy at home?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Close the window curtains during the day in the summer",
            "X": "Open the curtains on south-facing windows during the day in the winter",
            "Y": "Hang his wet clothes on clotheslines outside when it is sunny",
            "Z": "Turn thermostats to a colder temperature during the summer"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A clothes dryer can be a high consumer of household electricity. Which of the following options is NOT a way in which to reduce energy consumption when using your clothes dryer?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Purchase a dryer model that has an ENERGY STAR label",
            "X": "Use the moisture sensor option, if you have one",
            "Y": "Clean the lint filter to improve the efficiency of the dryer",
            "Z": "Scrub the lint filter if you use dryer sheets"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following best defines biodiesel?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Ethanol",
            "X": "Raw vegetable oil",
            "Y": "Alternative diesel fuel produced from renewable resources",
            "Z": "U.S. diesel fuel"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Gas to liquids, or GTL, fuels are produced by converting natural gas into liquid fuels. Which of the following is NOT a benefit for production and use of GTL fuels?  W) They are cleaner than conventional petroleum-based diesel fuel X) They are compatible with the current petroleum infrastructure Y) They can be produced domestically Z) GTL plants are relatively inexpensive to build",
        "Answer": "Z) GTL PLANTS ARE RELATIVELY INEXPENSIVE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Bioplastics are plastics derived from plant sources, rather than petroleum. Which of the following is NOT a way in which bioplastics can be made?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Intracellular production by the fermentation of a feedstock",
            "X": "Engineering a crop to grow the plastic within the plant itself",
            "Y": "Fermentation of a cereal to make precursors, which would then be processed into bioplastics",
            "Z": "Fermentation of the waste water from the conventional manufacture of corn syrup"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT an accurate representation of a limitation on the production and use of bioplastics?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Using crops to produce plastic diverts plants from the food supply",
            "X": "Bioplastics are unlikely to disintegrate in a landfill",
            "Y": "Bioplastics produce a variety of pollutants when burned",
            "Z": "Individuals at home would find it difficult to compost bioplastics"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Where is most of the uranium used in the United States mined?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "United States",
            "X": "Middle East",
            "Y": "Africa",
            "Z": "South America"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Uranium is usually found in trace concentrations, so it generally has to be extracted from uranium ore. Name the term for concentrated uranium oxide, which can vary in color from yellow, orange, and dark green to brown and black, produced from uranium ore in the uranium recovery process.",
        "Answer": "YELLOWCAKE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following forms of energy does NOT require bulk motion of physical matter through space?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Radiant",
            "X": "Nuclear",
            "Y": "Electrical",
            "Z": "Hydropower"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Ionizing radiation, which can penetrate cells and create ions in cell contents, is generated by which two kinds of electromagnetic radiation?",
        "Answer": "X-RAYS AND GAMMA RAYS  ________________________________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The largest reserve of energy in the United States is in which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Natural gas",
            "X": "Coal",
            "Y": "Nuclear",
            "Z": "Offshore oil"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC) produces about what percentage of the world\u00d5s crude oil?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "20%",
            "X": "40%",
            "Y": "60%",
            "Z": "80%"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the final three-carbon product of glycolysis?",
        "Answer": "PYRUVATE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Which acidic compound is the major product of fermentation in skeletal muscle?",
        "Answer": "LACTIC ACID"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Ocean thermal energy conversion systems convert solar radiation to electric power. Which of the following describes the source of energy in ocean thermal energy conversion systems?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Magma below the ocean floor",
            "X": "Oceanic thermal vents",
            "Y": "Wave motion",
            "Z": "The difference in temperatures between surface and deep waters"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What is the minimum temperature difference, in degrees Celsius, needed to develop an ocean thermal energy conversion system?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "10\u00fb",
            "X": "15\u00fb",
            "Y": "20\u00fb",
            "Z": "25\u00fb"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The typical efficiency of an automobile engine is approximately which of the following percentages?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "95",
            "X": "65",
            "Y": "25",
            "Z": "5"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Mechanical power produced by wind turbines needs to be converted into electrical energy before it can be used. What is necessary to accomplish this conversion?",
        "Answer": "GENERATOR  ________________________________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following types of coal is of high quality and has the highest energy content?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Subbituminous (read as: suhb-bi-tuh-MI-nehs)",
            "X": "Bituminous (read as: bi-TUH-mi-nehs)",
            "Y": "Lignite (read as: LIG-nyt)",
            "Z": "Peat"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Burning wood leads to the release of chemical energy via the process of oxidation. Which of the following describes this more accurately?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Wood \" (read as: yields) Fire",
            "X": "Wood + Oxygen \" (read as: yields) Carbon Dioxide + Water + Energy",
            "Y": "Wood + Oxygen \" (read as: yields) Coal + Carbon Dioxide + Energy",
            "Z": "Wood + Oxygen \" (read as: yields) Carbon Dioxide + Water + Sulfur Dioxide + Energy"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "When a ball rolls on a pool table, it eventually stops moving because of friction between the ball and the table. In this case, the kinetic energy of the ball has been converted to what other form of energy?",
        "Answer": "HEAT"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Plug-in hybrid electric vehicles are:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Completely powered by electricity",
            "X": "Powered by electricity until batteries are discharged and then powered by gasoline",
            "Y": "Completely powered by solar energy",
            "Z": "Powered completely by biofuels"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following produces the largest share of electric power generation in the U.S.?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Natural gas",
            "X": "Coal",
            "Y": "Nuclear power",
            "Z": "Hydropower"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Methane hydrate is a cage-like lattice of ice inside which are trapped molecules of methane, the chief constituent of natural gas. Which of the following is NOT true about methane hydrate?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Deposits generally occur beneath Arctic permafrost and the ocean floor",
            "X": "Methane extraction from methane hydrate has been documented in large-scale field experiments",
            "Y": "If pressures are high enough, it is stable far above the melting point of water ice",
            "Z": "The energy content of methane hydrate is very high"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Petroleum comes from:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Accumulated carbon rich plant materials",
            "X": "Dinosaur remains",
            "Y": "Meteorite rocks that impacted the Earth millions of years ago found deep underground",
            "Z": "Organic sediment transformed over time by bacteria, pressure, and temperature"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Unleaded gasoline pumped at a filling station comes from crude oil. About what percentage of the oil\u00d5s original energy content is present in gasoline when it is pumped into the vehicle at the station?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "13%",
            "X": "36%",
            "Y": "50%",
            "Z": "86%"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Of the following choices, what is the primary direct use of geothermal energy?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Aquaculture",
            "X": "Space heating",
            "Y": "Gold mining",
            "Z": "Dehydration of vegetable and fruit products"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Aquaculture applications for geothermal energy are particularly promising for all of the following reasons, except:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "A variety of freshwater or marine organisms can be raised",
            "X": "There is an abundance of geothermal resources at the required temperature range",
            "Y": "Consistent water temperatures increase survival rates",
            "Z": "Consistent water circulation enables year-round harvesting of consistently-sized fish"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In terms of energy, which of the following happens after a skydiver reaches terminal velocity?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Kinetic energy increases exponentially with distance",
            "X": "Gravitational potential energy ceases to be present",
            "Y": "Gravitational potential energy is converted into thermal energy",
            "Z": "Kinetic energy increases linearly with distance"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Non-hydraulic elevators typically use very small motors and block and tackle pulleys. What system component helps reduce the amount of the car\u00d5s weight that the motor has to lift?",
        "Answer": "COUNTERBALANCE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Absorption refrigeration is commonly used in co-generation facilities. It differs from traditional compressor refrigeration by which of the following key characteristics?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Size",
            "X": "It is heat-sourced",
            "Y": "It is electrically-sourced",
            "Z": "Temperature"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "By name or number, order the following four fuels from least to greatest amount of carbon dioxide produced annually from stationary combustion in the United States: 1) wood, 2) coal, 3) natural gas, 4) kerosene.",
        "Answer": "NATURAL GAS, KEROSENE, WOOD, COAL"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following BEST describes the process of coal liquefaction?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It converts coal into synthetic fuels",
            "X": "It reduces carbon dioxide emissions in coal plants",
            "Y": "It removes sulfur from coal in coal plants",
            "Z": "It converts coal into an easily transportable form"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is a disadvantage of flexible fuel vehicles?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "They get about 25% fewer miles per gallon when fueled with E85",
            "X": "They experience significant loss in power when operating on E85",
            "Y": "They are very different than gasoline-only models",
            "Z": "The technology is untested"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Biodiesel generally outperforms regular petro diesel in all of the following categories, EXCEPT:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Cetane rating",
            "X": "Flash point",
            "Y": "Calorific value",
            "Z": "Sulfur content"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The backup controls for a solar cell operate on a 4-volt lithium ion battery with resistance of 20 ohms and an initial capacity of 3000 milliampere hours. In watt hours, what is the electrical energy required to recharge the battery?",
        "Answer": "12 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A 5-kilogram mass is moving along a frictionless surface with a velocity of 10 meters per second toward a horizontal spring with a spring constant of 500 newtons per meter. What is the maximum compression of the spring in meters?",
        "Answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT an example of smart grid technology?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Ground-source heat pumps",
            "X": "Advanced metering infrastructure",
            "Y": "Conservation voltage reduction",
            "Z": "Substation automation"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Which hydroelectric dam has the greatest power capacity in the world?",
        "Answer": "THREE GORGES DAM"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Two men tried to lift a 95-kilogram sack of grain to a storage room on the second floor using ropes. Just as the sack reached the second floor, the rope broke and the sack dropped and hit the ground. The kinetic energy of the sack was 3500 joules just before it struck the ground. Given g as 9.8 meters per second squared and providing your answer to the nearest meter, what was the height of the second floor?",
        "Answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Crates A and B have equal mass and travel the same distance on a horizontal track while a constant force F acts on A and a constant force 2F acts on B. Both crates start from rest. Which of the following equations represents the velocities VA and VB of A and B at the end of the displacement?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "VB = VA/2",
            "X": "VB = !VA",
            "Y": "VB = 2VA",
            "Z": "VB = 4VA"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A 100 kilogram roller coaster starts from rest at a height of 500 meters. Given g as 10 meters per second squared and no friction, what speed in meters per second will it achieve at the bottom?",
        "Answer": "100 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Transformer efficiency is lowered, primarily due to power loss, at which of the following locations?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The load",
            "X": "The source",
            "Y": "The core",
            "Z": "The grounding point"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "For many household appliances, a step-down transformer is used. If such a transformer has an input of 120 volts and 0.6 amperes, and an output of 24 volts, what is the maximum possible output current in amperes?",
        "Answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What kind of chemical reaction is used to produce methane from algae decomposition?",
        "Answer": "ANAEROBIC DIGESTION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "You\u00d5re designing a battery pack filled with many cell phone lithium-ion batteries capable of storing 500 megawatt hours of energy. If the battery operates at a constant voltage of 3.6 volts, providing your answer in scientific notation with two significant figures, what capacity in ampere hours would you need to store 500 megawatt hours of energy?",
        "Answer": "1.4 ! 108"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A combination of technologies called the Sahara Forest Project with the potential to produce commercial quantities of food and energy crops, fresh water, and electricity in the desert, has all of the following components, EXCEPT:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Seawater greenhouse",
            "X": "Condensation collectors",
            "Y": "Cultivation of switchgrass",
            "Z": "Steam turbine generator"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In electron energy-loss spectroscopy, at energies equal to the inner-shell binding energies, typically in hundreds to thousands of electron volts, inner-shell excitation of electrons gives rise to what kind of edges?",
        "Answer": "IONIZATION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What kind of antimatter was first trapped and studied at CERN in November of 2010?",
        "Answer": "ANTIHYDROGEN"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Give the power rating of a household appliance, in watts, if the cost of continuously running it for 30 days at 10 cents per kilowatt hour is $36.",
        "Answer": "500 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In an AC circuit, if the voltage and current are 90 degrees out of phase, what term can be used to describe the load?",
        "Answer": "REACTIVE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following components is the greatest contributor to no-load losses on transformers?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Eddy current losses in the core laminations",
            "X": "Heat losses due to no-load current",
            "Y": "Dielectric losses",
            "Z": "Hysteresis losses"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Approximately how much energy does the Sun generate in joules per hour if it converts about 4 billion kilograms of mass into pure energy every second?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "109",
            "X": "1018",
            "Y": "1030",
            "Z": "1033"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In the presence of alcohol dehydrogenase, the rate of reduction of acetaldehyde to ethanol increases as you increase the concentration of acetaldehyde. Eventually, the rate of reaction reaches a maximum, where further increases in the concentration of acetaldehyde have no effect. Which of the following BEST explains this result?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "All of the alcohol dehydrogenase molecules are bound to acetaldehyde molecules",
            "X": "At high concentrations of acetaldehyde, the activation energy of the reaction decreases",
            "Y": "The enzyme is no longer specific for acetaldehyde",
            "Z": "At high concentrations of acetaldehyde, the change in free energy of the reaction decreases"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the term for a kind of landfill technology, currently in research and development, that accelerates the biological decomposition of organic wastes in a landfill by promoting the conditions necessary for the microorganisms that degrade the waste?",
        "Answer": "BIOREACTOR"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "When water levels drop in a spent nuclear fuel pool, temperatures in the fuel assembly rise, accelerating the oxidation of the material that encases uranium oxide pellets. If the oxidation reactions become self-sustaining, a fire can form that proceeds as a burn front along the axis of the fuel rod toward the source of the oxidant. What is the name of the encasing material that is burning?",
        "Answer": "ZIRCONIUM CLADDING"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Roughly, which of the following BEST represents the solar energy intensity in watts per square meter incident on the Earth?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "200",
            "X": "1,400",
            "Y": "3,000",
            "Z": "10,000"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Companies A, B, and C are forced to pay one dollar of tax per ton of carbon dioxide equivalent emissions. If Company A emits 100 tons of carbon dioxide and 4 tons of nitrous oxide, Company B emits 10 tons of carbon dioxide and 5 tons of nitrous oxide, and Company C emits 200 tons of carbon dioxide and no nitrous oxide, which company has to pay the largest tax?",
        "Answer": "COMPANY B"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What specific compound has emerged as a potential redox active material choice for two-step thermochemical cycling due to its rapid fuel production kinetics and high selectivity?",
        "Answer": "CERIUM"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A nuclear power plant is situated on the bank of a river. The power plant produces 200 megawatts of power and releases 1.5 ! 1013 joules of heat per day into the river through the cooling system. If the flow rate of the river is 5.0 ! 104 kilograms per second and the specific heat of water is 4.2 ! 103 joules per kilogram degree Celsius, what is the maximum temperature increase of the river water due to the cooling system, in degrees Celsius to the nearest integer?",
        "Answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Plasmas are considered strongly coupled when the ratio of the average distance between the particles to the distance of closest approach is which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Small",
            "X": "Large",
            "Y": "Roughly equal to one",
            "Z": "Roughly equal to zero"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Assuming an equal concentration of each substance, by name or number, order the following four choices in terms of radiative forcing, from greatest to least: 1) carbon dioxide, 2) methane, 3) fluorocarbons, 4) nitrous oxide.",
        "Answer": "FLUOROCARBONS, NITROUS OXIDE, METHANE, CARBON DIOXIDE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT an advantage of radio-frequency accelerators?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The technology is well established",
            "X": "Emittance dominates transverse beam dynamics during acceleration and storage, rather than space charge",
            "Y": "Obtaining the required ion energy is straightforward due to the high acceleration gradients in radio-frequency structures",
            "Z": "Storage rings are not needed since beams can be compressed in length as they are accelerated"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "By name or number, order the following processes from first to last in a gas turbine operating under an actual Brayton cycle: 1) heat rejection, 2) expansion, 3) heat addition, 4) compression.",
        "Answer": "COMPRESSION, HEAT ADDITION, EXPANSION, HEAT REJECTION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the term for the liquid, consisting of precipitation and waste decomposition, that has been filtered through a landfill?",
        "Answer": "LEACHATE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the name of an energy storage technology in which electrical energy is stored by accelerating a rotor, maintaining the energy in the system as rotational energy?",
        "Answer": "FLYWHEEL"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What element is the primary component of most photovoltaic cells?",
        "Answer": "SILICON"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What do we call the point in time when the maximum rate of global petroleum extraction is reached, after which the rate of production declines?",
        "Answer": "PEAK OIL"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the SI unit of magnetic flux?",
        "Answer": "WEBER"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "By name or number, rank the following four countries in annual geothermal energy generation as a percentage of total domestic energy production from least to greatest: 1) Kenya, 2) United States, 3) Mexico, 4) Iceland.",
        "Answer": "UNITED STATES, MEXICO, KENYA, ICELAND"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What kind of coal is rated poor for its heating value because of its low carbon content of 25 to 35 percent?",
        "Answer": "LIGNITE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "By name or number, rank the energy efficiency of the following four lighting technologies from least to most efficient: 1) light emitting diodes, 2) incandescent, 3) neon, 4) compact fluorescent.",
        "Answer": "INCANDESCENT, NEON, COMPACT FLUORESCENT, AND LIGHT EMITTING DIODES"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Tidal energy is difficult to practically harness because the difference between high tide and low tide needs to be at least 16 feet. What country is the largest producer of electricity from tidal energy?",
        "Answer": "FRANCE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the name of the process by which impurities are added to an intrinsic semiconductor to modulate its electrical properties?",
        "Answer": "DOPING _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following does NOT represent a potential benefit of smart grids?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Facilitation of the use of plug-in hybrids and electric vehicles",
            "X": "Optimization of power plant utilization",
            "Y": "Integration of renewable energy sources",
            "Z": "Uni-directional metering"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Taking the speed of light to be 300,000,000 meters per second, about how much energy in kilowatt hours is given by converting 1 nanogram of mass into energy?",
        "Answer": "25 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "An RLC circuit must contain of all of the following, EXCEPT:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "A capacitor",
            "X": "An inductor",
            "Y": "A diode",
            "Z": "A resistor"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "By name or number, identify all of the following four factors that directly affect the amount of electricity generated from hydroelectric dams: 1) water temperature, 2) flow, 3) head, 4) time of day.",
        "Answer": "FLOW AND HEAD"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following statements is NOT true about the current electricity system in the United States?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It is 99.7% reliable",
            "X": "It consists of more than 9,000 electric generating units",
            "Y": "It has more than 1,000,000 megawatts of generating capacity",
            "Z": "It is largely decentralized"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Taking the latent heat of fusion to be 80 calories per gram, how much energy, in kilocalories, does it take to bring 10 grams of ice at 0\u00a1 Celsius to liquid water at 20\u00a1 Celsius?",
        "Answer": "1 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "As the grade of coal increases, how do the concentrations of carbon and sulfur change, respectively?",
        "Answer": "CARBON INCREASES AND SULFUR DECREASES"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If burned over the course of a minute, providing your answer to the nearest ten, about how many kilowatts of power would a pound of human fat release?",
        "Answer": "240"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following characteristics make universal motors attractive for home appliances?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "High speed and low torque",
            "X": "High speed and high torque",
            "Y": "Low speed and high torque",
            "Z": "Low speed and low torque"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Taking g to be 9.8 meters per second squared, a 500 kilogram elevator needs how much energy, in kilojoules, to go up 30 meters, a typical height for the 10th floor?",
        "Answer": "147 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Pure hydrogen is an energy carrier rather than a primary source of energy, because it lacks which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Natural occurrence",
            "X": "Sufficient heat",
            "Y": "Energy density",
            "Z": "Radiant emission"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Excluding the Middle East, which of the following regions has the most proven oil reserves?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "North America",
            "X": "Central and South America",
            "Y": "Eurasia",
            "Z": "Africa"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is measured by total harmonic distortion, a standard for gauging the quality of power provided to customers?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "How distorted the waveform is from a pure sinusoidal waveform",
            "X": "How distorted a waveform is from a triangular waveform",
            "Y": "The difference between a sinusoidal waveform and a triangular waveform",
            "Z": "The maximum value of a sinusoidal waveform with respect to the reference point of the waveform"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Protists are classified by how they acquire energy. What is the specific phrase used to describe the diffusion of nutrients into the organisms after they have digested organic compounds through the secretion of exoenzymes?",
        "Answer": "HETEROTROPHIC ABSORPTION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following BEST represents the percentage of global oil reserves located in North America?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "5",
            "X": "10",
            "Y": "15",
            "Z": "20"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "To study fuel and water use by migrating birds, what controlled environment do researchers use in order to assess fat stores, protein mass, water, and immunological function when birds fly long distances?",
        "Answer": "WIND TUNNEL _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following energy generation methods is the BEST source for baseload?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Hydroelectric",
            "X": "Wind",
            "Y": "Solar",
            "Z": "Tidal turbines"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If 50.0 grams of water cools from 35.10\u00a1 Celsius to 26.05\u00a1 Celsius, providing your answer to the nearest hundred, how much heat is released in joules?",
        "Answer": "1,900"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Which country supplies the U.S. with 95% of its needed rare earth elements, key components in electronics, solar panels, and hybrid cars?",
        "Answer": "CHINA"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What kinds of electromagnetic emissions from the Crab Nebula were so stable that they were used for decades to calibrate space-borne instruments?",
        "Answer": "X-RAY"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT an advantage of using liquefied petroleum gas in vehicles instead of conventional gasoline?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It produces fewer toxic and smog-forming air pollutants",
            "X": "Most liquefied petroleum gas comes from domestic sources",
            "Y": "It is less expensive than gasoline",
            "Z": "It gets more miles per tank of fuel than conventional gasoline"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Given the reaction C3H8(g) + 5O2(g) ! (read as: yields) 4H2O(l) + 3CO2(g) occurs at room temperature with a  change in enthalpy of  -290,000 joules and change in entropy of -110 joules per Kelvin, what is the delta G in joules for this reaction and is the reaction spontaneous?",
        "Answer": "-277,500; SPONTANEOUS  [NOTE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "According to Betz\u00d5s Law, wind turbines cannot capture more than what approximate percentage of the kinetic energy present in wind?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "29",
            "X": "39",
            "Y": "49",
            "Z": "59"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT an advantage of vertical axis wind turbines as compared to horizontal axis wind turbines?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "They can catch the wind from all directions",
            "X": "They can catch the wind at lower wind speeds",
            "Y": "They are typically more efficient at converting wind energy into electricity",
            "Z": "They are more suited to urban environments"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "To reduce total energy consumption in the home, in which of the following locations should insulation with the highest R-value be installed?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Walls",
            "X": "Attic",
            "Y": "Crawlspace",
            "Z": "Kitchen"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "An electronic device operates on a 1.5 volt battery with a resistance of 10 ohms. If the initial capacity of this battery is 1400 milliampere-hours, and providing your answer as a decimal to the nearest tenth, for how many hours of continuous use could this device operate?",
        "Answer": "9.3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In the nuclear fission process to create electricity, Uranium 235 is split into many different products including thorium, protactinium, and actinium. With what stable element does it eventually end its decay chain?",
        "Answer": "LEAD"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following vehicle engine technologies improves engine fuel efficiency the most?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Cylinder deactivation",
            "X": "Direct fuel injection and a turbocharger",
            "Y": "Integrated starter/generator",
            "Z": "Variable valve timing and lift"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the purpose of a fuel cell stack in a fuel cell vehicle?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Store hydrogen gas compressed at extremely high pressure to increase driving range",
            "X": "Govern the flow of electricity",
            "Y": "Store energy generated from regenerative braking",
            "Z": "Convert hydrogen and oxygen gas into electricity to power the electric motor"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In an experiment, students find the relationship between the period of a stick vibrating at its natural frequency and the length L of the stick, measuring the period of the vibrations with a photogate. Which of the following statements BEST reflects the results of the experiment with regard to the period of the vibrating stick?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It is proportional to L",
            "X": "It is inversely proportional to L",
            "Y": "It is proportional to L2",
            "Z": "It is inversely proportional to L2"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In an experiment, students burned samples of methanol, ethanol, vegetable oil, peanut oil, and kerosene. Which two were the cleanest burning?",
        "Answer": "METHANOL AND ETHANOL"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What kind of compound consists of methane surrounded by a crystal cage of water molecules, forming a solid similar to ice?",
        "Answer": "METHANE CLATHRATE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "When traveling at the same speed, which of the following fission products has the greatest kinetic energy?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "A neutron",
            "X": "An alpha particle",
            "Y": "A beta particle",
            "Z": "A positron"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Name all of the following four choices that are types of coal: 1) lignite, 2) bituminous [by-TOO-muh-nuhs], 3) dolomite, 4) anthracite [AN-thruh-syt].",
        "Answer": "1, 2, 4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following power types demonstrates large scale temporary storage of energy?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Coal",
            "X": "Chemical",
            "Y": "Hydroelectric",
            "Z": "Wind"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The insides of vacuum chambers are frequently mirrored; what form of heat transfer does this prevent?",
        "Answer": "RADIATIVE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "One of the criticisms of ground-mount solar farms is the amount of space they occupy. A new solar system was recently announced called \ufb01floatovoltaics,\ufb02 because it is a floating solar farm. Which of the following is NOT a potential benefit of this system?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Reducing evaporation",
            "X": "Reducing algae growth",
            "Y": "Short-term profitability",
            "Z": "Increasing solar panel power production"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "When Iodine-131 is ingested, which organ most readily absorbs it and can potentially be damaged by it?",
        "Answer": "THYROID"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Powerful X-ray technology developed at DOE national laboratories is revealing new insights into diseases ranging from Alzheimer\u2122s to swine flu. This X-ray crystallography [kris-tl-OG-ruh-fee] has been used for all EXCEPT which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Revealing the structures of diseased and disease-causing molecules",
            "X": "Creating three-dimensional maps of mutated enzymes",
            "Y": "Producing scattered, low intensity X-ray beams to surround the surface of the molecules",
            "Z": "Allowing medical researchers to develop drugs to prevent mutated enzymes from triggering cancer cells"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Several types of geologic formations can serve as a storage reservoir [REZ-er-vwohr] for carbon. Which of the following formations is an example of this type of storage?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Fresh water reservoir",
            "X": "Deep saline reservoir",
            "Y": "Ocean reservoir",
            "Z": "Granitic plateaus [pla-TOHZ]"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following geothermal power plant types uses steam directly from the ground to spin a turbine?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Binary cycle",
            "X": "Flash steam",
            "Y": "Dry steam",
            "Z": "Hybrid steam"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If the solar power incident over 1 square meter at 1 au from the Sun is 1000 watts, what level in watts will it achieve at 2 au?",
        "Answer": "250"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following statements is NOT true?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Gas stoves with electronic ignition use much less energy than older models with pilot lights",
            "X": "Using the self-cleaning cycles regularly in your oven increases overall energy savings",
            "Y": "Microwaves and toaster ovens cook meals with less power than most traditional ovens",
            "Z": "Cooktops work more efficiently when they are clean"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Many consider the start of the U.S. natural gas industry to have occurred in 1859, when a 69-foot well in Pennsylvania struck natural gas and oil. Who is credited with drilling this well?",
        "Answer": "EDWIN DRAKE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "When processing mined uranium ore, it is first crushed to a fine powder and then processed with concentrated acid, alkaline, or peroxide solutions to leach out the uranium. What is the common term for the remaining coarse powder?",
        "Answer": "YELLOWCAKE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following metabolites has the most negative standard Gibbs free energy of hydrolysis [hy-DROL-uh-sis]?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Phosphocreatine [fohs-foh-KREE-uh-teen]",
            "X": "Pyrophosphate [py-roh-FOS-fayt]",
            "Y": "Glucose 1-phosphate",
            "Z": "Phosphoenolpyruvate [fohs-foh-uh-nol-py-ROO-vayt]"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following was NOT an effect of removing sulfur from diesel fuel?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It lowered the nitrous oxides and soot emissions",
            "X": "It slightly increased gas mileage in diesel engines",
            "Y": "It allowed the use of advanced emissions control systems",
            "Z": "It reduced the lubricity of the fuel"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following most accurately describes an advantage of a nuclear fusion reactor over a nuclear fission reactor?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "A failure of control systems shuts down the fusion reactor",
            "X": "Fusion based nuclear plants are much less expensive than fission plants",
            "Y": "Fusion reactors operate at a lower temperature than fission reactors",
            "Z": "The fuel rods in the fusion reactor can be reused"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What microscopy technique uses energy transfer between two molecules to measure the distance between the molecules?",
        "Answer": "FLUORESCENCE RESONANCE ENERGY TRANSFER"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Fatty acid synthesis uses which of the following kinds of metabolic pathways?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Spiral",
            "X": "Branched",
            "Y": "Linear",
            "Z": "Cyclic"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Neutrons in fission reactors are categorized based on their origin. What term describes neutrons emitted directly from a fission event, rather than from a subsequent or unrelated decay event?",
        "Answer": "PROMPT"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How much heat energy in BTUs is needed to heat 200 pounds of water from 50 degrees to 130 degrees Fahrenheit?",
        "Answer": "16,000"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Gasoline is sold as \ufb01unleaded gas,\ufb02 which is a misnomer because gasoline does not naturally contain lead. Lead was added to gasoline from the 1940s to 1980s. What was the reason for adding lead to gasoline?",
        "Answer": "STOP ENGINE KNOCK"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Given g as 10 meters per second squared, how much power in megawatts can a perfectly efficient dam 100 meters high produce if 2000 kilograms of water pass through its turbines every second?",
        "Answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "OTEC is which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "A method of producing hydrogen gas using solar energy",
            "X": "A form of tidal energy that harnesses the ebb and flow of ocean water",
            "Y": "An organization of oil-rich countries",
            "Z": "A method of energy generation from the thermal gradient of ocean waters"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "There are several ways to store wind energy for non-windy days. Which of the following methods is NOT currently being used?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Pumping air into underground storage",
            "X": "Pumping water up to elevated storage and then releasing it to drive an electric generator",
            "Y": "Pumping water into underground storage",
            "Z": "Charging batteries"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following nuclides is both fissile and fissionable only with high energy bombardment?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "U-233",
            "X": "U-235",
            "Y": "U-238",
            "Z": "Pu-239"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Name the process, suggested as a possible avenue for cold fusion to occur, in which a sound wave is passed through a bubble in a jar, causing the bubble to expand and collapse.",
        "Answer": "SONOLUMINESCENCE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "When the spent fuel is removed from a nuclear power plant, which of the following immediately occurs?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It is placed in dry cask storage at the nuclear reactor site until it is safe to handle, and then it is sent to the permanent storage facility",
            "X": "It is sent to Yucca Mountain to be stored in the National Repository",
            "Y": "It is stored under water in a spent fuel pool at the reactor for several years",
            "Z": "It is sealed in 50 gallon drums and allowed to cool"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following statements is NOT true about bubble chambers?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "They consist of tanks of superheated transparent liquid",
            "X": "As charged beam particles pass through the liquid, the liquid boils along their paths",
            "Y": "When the pressure is decreased, the bubbles clear",
            "Z": "The bubbles are allowed to grow until they have a diameter of about 1 millimeter"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following effects does lowering the temperature have on the decay rate of a sample of radioactive material?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The decay will speed up",
            "X": "The decay will slow down",
            "Y": "There is no change",
            "Z": "There is an inverse relationship between temperature and fission"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "FutureGen 2.0 power plants will reduce carbon dioxide production by burning coal in which of the following ways?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "With a mixture of oxygen and carbon dioxide instead of air to produce concentrated carbon dioxide",
            "X": "With an enhanced concentration of oxygen instead of air to produce less carbon dioxide per ton of coal burned",
            "Y": "In a catalytic chamber that scrubs the carbon dioxide out of the emissions",
            "Z": "Using carbon dioxide reduced coal in an 80% nitrogen and 18% oxygen mixture"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If you heat a container of gas at a higher temperature than its surroundings to twice its prior absolute temperature without changing the temperature of its environment, you have done which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Increased the system's enthalpy and decreased its entropy",
            "X": "Increased the system's enthalpy and entropy",
            "Y": "Decreased the system's enthalpy and entropy",
            "Z": "Decreased the system's enthalpy and increased its entropy"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the name of the technique used to enrich gaseous U-235 after it has been combined with fluorine?",
        "Answer": "CENTRIFUGATION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Nanticoke Generating Station, located in southern Ontario, Canada, is one of the world's largest coal-burning power plants. However, the Canadian Ministry of Energy announced in 2010 that Nanticoke would convert some of their generators to use which of the following types of fuel instead of coal?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Natural gas",
            "X": "Uranium-238",
            "Y": "Petroleum",
            "Z": "Ethanol"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A liquid metal fast reactor (LMFR) is an advanced type of nuclear reactor that uses liquid metal as a primary coolant. Of the following metals, which one is NOT most commonly used as a primary coolant in LMFRs?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Lithium",
            "X": "Mercury",
            "Y": "Lead",
            "Z": "Sodium"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT a potential source of biogas?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Landfills",
            "X": "Sewage treatment plants",
            "Y": "Automobile engine",
            "Z": "Animal waste"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The presence of which of the following traits is required for the creation of all oil traps?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Anticline",
            "X": "Syncline",
            "Y": "Impermeable layer",
            "Z": "Fault"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is typically increased in order for electricity to travel long distances through transmission lines?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Voltage",
            "X": "Amperage",
            "Y": "Wattage",
            "Z": "Current"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What type of semi-conducting junction is essential to the functioning of a solar cell?",
        "Answer": "P-N JUNCTION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following describes the purpose of the ground connection on a common power outlet?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Provide a zero potential reference",
            "X": "Remove excess heat from the transmission system",
            "Y": "Give a low resistance path for short circuits to travel through",
            "Z": "Act as a small current source to prevent corrosion"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If a solar panel produces energy directly proportional to the flux of incident photons, what is the best orientation it can have, relative to the line from the Earth to the Sun?",
        "Answer": "PERPENDICULAR"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following uses stored electricity and is required to get a gasoline-powered car's engine going?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Catalytic converter",
            "X": "Starter motor",
            "Y": "Fuel rail",
            "Z": "Alternator"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Most coals of the softer varieties are forms of which of the three major rock types?",
        "Answer": "SEDIMENTARY"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In 1859, drilling first began in the U.S. for which of the following energy resources?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Coal",
            "X": "Oil",
            "Y": "Natural gas",
            "Z": "Geothermal energy"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In what kind of electrochemical cell would copper and zinc plates be lowered into a sulfuric acid solution in order to generate an electric current?",
        "Answer": "VOLTAIC"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is a product from a hydrogen fuel reaction?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Water",
            "X": "Carbon dioxide",
            "Y": "Methane",
            "Z": "Nitrogen"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What value is used to describe the heat resistance of home insulation?",
        "Answer": "R-VALUE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following energy resources is the most energy efficient, meaning very little of the energy created is transferred to the surroundings unused?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Coal",
            "X": "Biofuel",
            "Y": "Oil",
            "Z": "Hydrogen fuel cells"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following statements is true about pure biodiesel, or B100?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "B100 has higher carbon dioxide emissions compared to petrodiesel",
            "X": "B100 is more toxic than petrodiesel",
            "Y": "Glycerin [GLIS-er-in] is a key byproduct created during biodiesel production",
            "Z": "B100 contains a small amount of petroleum"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following statements about coal is true?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Over 50% of the coal mined in the United States is bituminous [by-TOO-muh-nuhs]",
            "X": "Lignite [LIG-nyt] has the highest energy content of all coal varieties",
            "Y": "Anthracite [AN-thruh-syt] contains approximately 25% carbon",
            "Z": "Lignite has a very low moisture content"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The United States utilizes two different types of commercial nuclear power plants: BWRs and PWRs. What is the full term for which BWR is the abbreviation?",
        "Answer": "BOILING WATER REACTOR"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is an example of a secondary energy source?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Coal",
            "X": "Electricity",
            "Y": "Solar",
            "Z": "Nuclear"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A water heater uses 4 kilowatts of electricity for 8 hours. To the nearest cent, how much does it cost to operate if the cost of electricity in your area is 10 cents per kilowatt hour?",
        "Answer": "$3.20"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the term for a device used to determine or measure the presence of electrostatic charges?",
        "Answer": "ELECTROSCOPE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the efficiency of an appliance whose useful energy output is 5 joules and wasted energy is 20 joules?",
        "Answer": "20%"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following particles has the least penetrating power?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Neutron",
            "X": "Alpha particle",
            "Y": "Beta particle",
            "Z": "Positron"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The power produced by a wind turbine depends primarily on which of the following parameters?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Air volume",
            "X": "Wind pressure",
            "Y": "Blade radius",
            "Z": "Air coefficient"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Rectifiers are used in computers and other appliances to do which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Convert direct current to alternating current",
            "X": "Convert alternating current to direct current",
            "Y": "Provide a steady amount of power at all times",
            "Z": "Reduce the energy consumption of an appliance"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "When inductors are present in circuits with alternating currents, what type of power do they consume?",
        "Answer": "REACTIVE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following terms would be used as a synonym for a building described with the term LEED?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Lead contaminated",
            "X": "Green",
            "Y": "Renewed",
            "Z": "Sanitized"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the term for the liquid or gas discharged after processing activities, such as in sewage treatment plants?",
        "Answer": "EFFLUENT"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following sectors in the U.S. uses the most petroleum?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Industry",
            "X": "Residential",
            "Y": "Transportation",
            "Z": "Construction"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following statements is true about the relationship between a BTU and a kilocalorie?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "A BTU has about one tenth the energy of a kilocalorie",
            "X": "A BTU has about one fourth the energy of a kilocalorie",
            "Y": "A BTU has about the same amount of energy as a kilocalorie",
            "Z": "A BTU has about 251 times the energy of a kilocalorie"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following will NOT usually increase the gas mileage of gasoline cars manufactured since the early 1980s?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Driving at or below 60 miles per hour on the freeway",
            "X": "Using cruise control",
            "Y": "Replacing clogged air filters",
            "Z": "Using overdrive gears"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A solar cell is an electrical device that converts light energy directly into electricity. What is the term for this conversion process?",
        "Answer": "PHOTOVOLTAIC EFFECT"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the term for a facility that integrates biomass conversion processes and equipment to produce fuels, power, and chemicals from biomass?",
        "Answer": "BIOREFINERY"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Name all of the following five products that have been made with green algae: 1) biodiesel, 2) methane, 3) ethanol, 4) gasoline, 5) biogasoline.",
        "Answer": "1, 2, 3, 5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A commercial scale gas atomizer will soon be developed in order to produce fine powder of what element, known for its strength, light weight, biocompatibility, and resistance to corrosion?",
        "Answer": "TITANIUM"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Biodiesel is made through a chemical process called transesterification [trans-uh-ster-uh-fi-KAY-shuhn]. Vegetable oil and methanol react to form biodiesel and what other byproduct?",
        "Answer": "GLYCERIN"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following conditions is NOT required to form coal?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "A stagnant and stable water level",
            "X": "Heat and pressure over a long period of time",
            "Y": "An equal supply of both vegetation and sediment",
            "Z": "A plant accumulation rate equaling land subsidence rate"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Why, aside from making it possible to push more energy through a line in a given unit of time, is power transmitted at higher voltages over longer distances?",
        "Answer": "TO REDUCE TRANSMISSION LOSS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT a result of mountaintop coal mining?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Increased mineral content in valley streams",
            "X": "Formation of new wetlands",
            "Y": "Reduction in amphibian populations",
            "Z": "Defragmentation of forests"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Lithium thionyl [THY-uh-nil] chloride batteries have low current delivery but long life spans. They are able to operate at a temperature range between -55\u00b0 Celsius and 150\u00b0 Celsius. Which of the following is least likely to be powered by a lithium thionyl chloride battery?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Speakers",
            "X": "Smoke detectors",
            "Y": "Diving equipment",
            "Z": "Wireless alarm systems"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What physical property is exploited when separating volatiles via fractional distillation?",
        "Answer": "BOILING POINT"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "At 23o Celsius and 1 atmosphere, what are the physical states, respectively, of ethane, butane, and octane?",
        "Answer": "ETHANE = GAS, BUTANE = GAS, OCTANE = LIQUID"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "By what process is gasoline separated from crude oil?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Distillation",
            "X": "Digestion",
            "Y": "Fracking",
            "Z": "Filtering"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What property of water allows it to have surface tension, and what is the intermolecular force responsible?",
        "Answer": "COHESION AND HYDROGEN"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following processes is currently used commercially to enrich uranium in the United States?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Gaseous diffusion",
            "X": "Gaseous centrifugation",
            "Y": "Metal plating",
            "Z": "Electrolysis"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Solvent-based techniques best capture carbon dioxide under which of the following relative conditions?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "High temperature, high pressure",
            "X": "High temperature, low pressure",
            "Y": "Low temperature, high pressure",
            "Z": "Low temperature, low pressure"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What is the major potential benefit of electric propulsion systems for the NASA space program?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "They are lighter than traditional fuels",
            "X": "They are less toxic than traditional fuels",
            "Y": "They contribute to an artificial gravity environment",
            "Z": "They require less research and development"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following advantages is offered by mid- and deep-ocean sequestration that is not possible at shallower depths?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Faster mineralization of carbon dioxide",
            "X": "Easier injection of carbon dioxide",
            "Y": "Buoyant carbon dioxide hydrates",
            "Z": "Longer residence time"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Volatile fossil fuels tend to have low carbon to hydrogen ratios. Which of the following fossil fuels is the most volatile?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Coal",
            "X": "Ethane",
            "Y": "Methane",
            "Z": "Petroleum"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Rank the following four fuels in terms of carbon dioxide intensity, from least to greatest: 1) coal, 2) natural gas, 3) ethanol, 4) biomass.",
        "Answer": "4, 3, 2, 1"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Acid rain is unusually acidic precipitation containing elevated levels of hydrogen ions. Which of the following emissions is NOT an emission from a power plant that would contribute to acid rain?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Carbon dioxide",
            "X": "Hydroxide",
            "Y": "Nitrogen oxide",
            "Z": "Sulfur dioxide"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following does NOT increase line losses from so-called \"corona\" effects?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Voltage",
            "X": "Elevation",
            "Y": "Precipitation",
            "Z": "Latitude"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the term for the lifetime cost of generating electricity that is inclusive of initial capital cost and discount rate, as well as operation, fuel, and maintenance costs?",
        "Answer": "LEVELIZED COST"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "When considering the total U.S. energy resources and reserves, coal represents 2.3% of the energy base. What approximate percentage does geothermal represent?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "14%",
            "X": "23%",
            "Y": "39%",
            "Z": "51%"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Growth in the production of what commodity has resulted in an excess of glycerine [GLIS-er-in]?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Gasoline",
            "X": "Natural gas",
            "Y": "Ethanol",
            "Z": "Biodiesel"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What is the approximate investment ratio per effective megawatt capacity for solar versus geothermally generated electricity?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "2",
            "X": "5",
            "Y": "8",
            "Z": "10"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The Marcellus shale gas formation is located in which of the following states?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Pennsylvania",
            "X": "Texas",
            "Y": "Oklahoma",
            "Z": "Wyoming"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Compounds of bismuth telluride are used in which of the following types of devices?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Photovoltaic devices",
            "X": "Computer chips",
            "Y": "Energy control devices",
            "Z": "Thermoelectric devices"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following explanations is used by scientists to justify the observed accelerating expansion of the universe?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Dark matter",
            "X": "Fast moving neutrinos",
            "Y": "Dark energy",
            "Z": "Supernovae [soo-per-NOH-vee]"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Power is being transmitted at 100,000 volts and the current flow is 20 amperes. What is the power loss in watts over 120 miles if the resistance of the power line is 0.5 ohms per mile?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "6,000",
            "X": "6,667",
            "Y": "12,000",
            "Z": "24,000"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Judged to be an intervention that delivers high impact per development dollar, improved cooking stoves aim to reduce greenhouse gas contribution by reducing the amount of what substance?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Carbon dioxide",
            "X": "Black carbon",
            "Y": "Methane",
            "Z": "Nitrous oxide"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT a common use for flue gas desulfurization [dee-suhl-fuh-ri-ZAY-shuhn] products?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Raw material for drywall",
            "X": "Raw material for plywood",
            "Y": "Fill for structural applications",
            "Z": "Feed stock in cement production"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "When dealing with a tank of 150 pounds of water on a platform, it is most energy intensive to do which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Lift the 150 pounds of water 2 feet in the air",
            "X": "Lower the 150 pounds of water by 2 feet",
            "Y": "Decrease the temperature of the water by 2\u00b0 Fahrenheit",
            "Z": "Increase the temperature of the water by 1\u00b0 Fahrenheit"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What process accounts for most of the Earth\u2122s geothermal energy?",
        "Answer": "RADIOACTIVE DECAY"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In northern climates, which component of a residential home, if properly insulated, will lead to maximal energy savings?",
        "Answer": "ATTIC"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In string theory, in the absence of external interactions, string dynamics are governed by tension and which of the following types of energy?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Kinetic",
            "X": "Chemical",
            "Y": "Electrostatic potential",
            "Z": "Gravitational potential"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What is the process by which lithium enters electrodes in a lithium-ion battery?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Intercalation",
            "X": "Precipitation",
            "Y": "Hydration",
            "Z": "Bombardment"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "While walking down the street, an open wire falls on you and you receive an instantaneous alternating current electric shock. Where did most of the electrons come from that \ufb01shocked\ufb02 you?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The ground",
            "X": "The wire",
            "Y": "The air",
            "Z": "Your body"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Whose equation describes the relationship between the concentration of an electro-active species and electric potential?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Ohm",
            "X": "Joule",
            "Y": "Nernst",
            "Z": "Bode"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Arrange the following four substances in order of decreasing energy content in kilocalories per gram: 1) proteins, 2) organic acids, 3) fats, 4) ethanol.",
        "Answer": "3, 4, 1, 2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Why do solid oxide fuel cells not require a precious metal catalyst or fuel reformer?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "They do not rely on the hydrogen-oxygen redox couple",
            "X": "They have a high operating temperature",
            "Y": "They have a very fast startup time",
            "Z": "They have a low operating temperature"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Graphene sheets, often used in solar cells and capacitors, have carbon rings with which type of lattice?",
        "Answer": "HEXAGONAL"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "As you turn on your flashlight, its lithium-ion battery begins to discharge. What happens to the electrons and ions inside the battery?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Both the electrons and the lithium ions move towards the cathode",
            "X": "Both the electrons and the lithium ions move towards the anode",
            "Y": "The electrons move towards the cathode while the lithium ions move towards the anode",
            "Z": "The electrons move towards the anode while the lithium ions move towards the cathode"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If a city had a yearly load of 438,000 megawatt hours and built a power plant with a capacity factor of 50%, what would the nameplate capacity have to be in megawatts in order to meet total load?",
        "Answer": "100"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following cooking pot materials is most useful for an induction cooktop?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Copper",
            "X": "Cast iron",
            "Y": "Aluminum",
            "Z": "Glass"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What functional unit in coal-based power production efficiently removes particulate matter?",
        "Answer": "ELECTROSTATIC PRECIPITATOR"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the electrode material of choice for capacitive deionization of seawater?",
        "Answer": "CARBON"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Microwave ovens work by creating radiation energy that is absorbed by the water, fats, and sugars in food, which in turn is converted to atomic motion and heat. Providing your answer in scientific notation with one significant figure, if the wavelength of microwave radiation is 10 centimeters, what is the frequency in hertz?",
        "Answer": "3 x 109"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Line losses vary linearly with what physical characteristic of power lines?",
        "Answer": "RESISTANCE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Arrange the following four sectors based on the number of tons of greenhouse gases released from smallest to largest: 1) Agriculture, 2) Residential, 3) Commercial, 4) Transportation.",
        "Answer": "1, 2, 3, 4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following equations best represents the conservation of energy in fluid systems?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Laplace",
            "X": "Bernoulli",
            "Y": "Navier-Stokes",
            "Z": "Euler"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "How many BTUs are required to raise 5 pounds of water from 40\u00b0 Fahrenheit to 120\u00b0 Fahrenheit with a stove that is 80% efficient?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "320",
            "X": "400",
            "Y": "450",
            "Z": "500"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following has long been considered the upper theoretical percentage limit for solar cell efficiency?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "24.5%",
            "X": "33.7%",
            "Y": "41.2%",
            "Z": "62.8%"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What property of hydrogen makes water a good neutron moderator?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It has a small neutron scattering cross section",
            "X": "It has a large neutron scattering cross section",
            "Y": "It is fissile",
            "Z": "It evaporates at 373 Kelvin"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In an isothermal system, what is one way that one can increase the number of interactions of a gas with a solid surface?",
        "Answer": "INCREASE PRESSURE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If yellow light has a wavelength of 550 nanometers, which of the following colors and associated wavelengths of light in nanometers is most energetic?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Violet, 700",
            "X": "Green, 500",
            "Y": "Red, 500",
            "Z": "Red, 700"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The Bakken Oil/Gas field is estimated to contain up to 24 billion barrels of oil. In which of the following states, among others, is it located?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "North Dakota",
            "X": "Oklahoma",
            "Y": "Pennsylvania",
            "Z": "Texas"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A DOE geothermal research project has established the effectiveness of enhanced geothermal systems (EGS) for utilizing geothermal energy for the generation of electricity. Using this approach, which of the following percentages of total U.S. current generating capacity could be generated with EGS?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "5%",
            "X": "15%",
            "Y": "25%",
            "Z": "50%"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The majority of moth species forage for food energy during what stage of their life cycle?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Egg",
            "X": "Larva",
            "Y": "Pupa",
            "Z": "Adult"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The electrical resistance of a semiconducting wire is least likely to be reduced by a decrease in which two of the following four wire characteristics? (1) melting point, (2) radius, (3) length, (4) temperature",
        "Answer": "1 and 2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Some prokaryotes [proh-KAR-ee-ohts] derive energy from inorganic compounds such as sulfides, hydrogen, or ammonia. What is this type of metabolism called?",
        "Answer": "CHEMOLITHOTROPHY"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Oxides of which two elements comprise most acid rain resulting from power generation?",
        "Answer": "NITROGEN AND SULFUR"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the least promising method of large-scale oil extraction in the next several decades?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Drilling access to underground oil reservoirs [REZ-er-vwahrs]",
            "X": "Acquiring oil from whales",
            "Y": "Acquiring oil from algae",
            "Z": "Acquiring oil produced by genetically re-engineered Escherichia coli [e-schuh-ri-KEE-uh koh-LY]"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Coal combustion products (CCPs) are solid materials produced when coal is burned to generate electricity. Which of the following is NOT a sustainable way to recycle CCPs?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Adding CCP to biodiesel",
            "X": "Using CCP as an agricultural fertilizer",
            "Y": "Adding CCP to concrete",
            "Z": "Adding CCP to asphalt"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Bond energy measures the strength of a chemical bond. Providing your answer in kilojoules per mole, what is the average bond energy of the C-H bonds in methane if it takes 1600 kilojoules to break up 1 mole of methane into 1 mole of carbon and 4 moles of hydrogen?",
        "Answer": "400"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Organisms are sometimes assigned fractional trophic levels. Which of the following factors is least likely to complicate trophic level assignment?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Female black widow spiders cannibalize male black widow spiders after mating",
            "X": "Bullfrogs eat crayfish while crayfish eat bullfrog tadpoles",
            "Y": "Bobcats eat rabbits while mountain lions eat both bobcats and rabbits",
            "Z": "Gorillas eat both bamboo and fruit"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Which type of metabolic pathway uses ATP to build macromolecules, such as proteins, out of smaller components?",
        "Answer": "ANABOLIC METABOLISM"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Although coal formed throughout many geological periods, coal from the Lower Triassic period is quite rare. Which of the following is the best possible explanation?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Terrestrial plants had not yet evolved",
            "X": "Large animals had not yet evolved",
            "Y": "A mass extinction occurred",
            "Z": "Soil density was too low"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What percentage of the world\u2122s geothermally produced electricity is produced in the United States?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "11%",
            "X": "17%",
            "Y": "24%",
            "Z": "30%"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT a type of vacuum pump?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Scroll pump",
            "X": "Roots blower",
            "Y": "Diaphragm compressor",
            "Z": "Turbomolecular pump"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following will generally cause the kinetics of a reaction to increase?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Decreasing surface area",
            "X": "Decreasing concentration",
            "Y": "Increasing temperature",
            "Z": "Increasing number of side reactions"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In megajoules, how much energy does a 2.5 kilowatt stove use if turned on for two hours?",
        "Answer": "18"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Line losses occur when electricity is transported long distances over transmission lines. Which of the following units is an appropriate measure for line losses?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Kilovolts per kilometer",
            "X": "Megawatts per mile",
            "Y": "Megaamperes per kilometer",
            "Z": "Volts-ampere"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Rare earth magnets are often used in the production of electrical energy. What percentage of world production of the rare earth materials used to produce these magnets was mined in the United States in 2011?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "0%",
            "X": "5%",
            "Y": "7%",
            "Z": "12%"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the name for the practice of reducing or shifting electricity usage during peak periods in response to time-based rates or other forms of financial incentives?",
        "Answer": "DEMAND RESPONSE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "At 100 volts, which of the following is closest to the amperage through a circuit that consists of the following in series: resistors of 10 ohms, 15 ohms, and 22 ohms followed by these resistors in parallel: 5, 10, 20, all in the same circuit.",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1.5",
            "X": "2.0",
            "Y": "2.5",
            "Z": "5.5"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Air source heat pumps rely on an evaporative and condensing intermediate fluid. What is the general term for this fluid?",
        "Answer": "REFRIGERANT"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following terms does NOT uniquely apply to the description of magnet properties?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Coercive force",
            "X": "Anisotropy [an-eye-suh-TROP-ik]",
            "Y": "Curie temperature",
            "Z": "Remanance [REM-uh-nuhns]"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the term for a rate structure where the cost of electricity is based on the time of day you use it?",
        "Answer": "TIME OF USE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Enhanced Geothermal Systems, developed by the DOE, increased the availability of geothermal generated electricity in the U.S. by what multiple?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "3",
            "X": "5",
            "Y": "10",
            "Z": "40"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the name of the energy storage method where water is pumped from a lower elevation reservoir to a higher elevation during off-peak periods, then released through turbines to produce electric power during peak periods?",
        "Answer": "PUMPED-STORAGE HYDROELECTRICITY"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Rank the following four sources of U.S. primary energy production in 2011 from greatest to least: 1) coal, 2) solar, 3) natural gas, 4) crude oil.",
        "Answer": "3, 1, 4, 2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What percentage of the world\u2122s production of rare earth metals is produced by China?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "57%",
            "X": "68%",
            "Y": "83%",
            "Z": "95%"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT a benefit of distributed generation?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Decreased transmission investment",
            "X": "Greater grid resiliency",
            "Y": "Elimination of distribution system investment",
            "Z": "Reduction in line losses"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If my current annual heating bill of natural gas is $800 with a furnace that is 70% efficient, approximately what will be my new bill if I install a 95% efficient furnace?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "$500",
            "X": "$600",
            "Y": "$700",
            "Z": "$800"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the term for the point at which solar photovoltaic technology produces power at a cost that is equal to the price of purchasing power from the grid?",
        "Answer": "GRID PARITY"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following methods of electricity production typically uses no water?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Solar thermal",
            "X": "Tidal",
            "Y": "Geothermal",
            "Z": "Photovoltaic"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If 100 joules of energy are added to a 5 kilogram substance and its temperature increases by 4 degrees Celsius, what is its specific heat capacity in joules per kilogram degrees Celsius?",
        "Answer": "5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What unit of energy is defined as the amount of heat needed to raise the temperature of one pound of water by one degree Fahrenheit?",
        "Answer": "BRITISH THERMAL UNIT"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "How would you classify a bacterium that derives its energy from inorganic sources such as hydrogen sulphide?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Chemoheterotroph [kee-moh-HET-er-uh-trof]",
            "X": "Chemoautotroph [kee-moh-AW-tuh-trof]",
            "Y": "Photoautotroph [foh-toh-AW-tuh-trof]",
            "Z": "Photoheterotroph [foh-toh-het-ER-uh-trof]"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What hazardous material enables compact fluorescent light bulbs to be more efficient while also requiring special disposal methods?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Tungsten",
            "X": "Lead",
            "Y": "Hafnium [HAF-nee-uhm]",
            "Z": "Mercury"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What device in a modern car allows the turning engine to recharge the car\u2122s battery while driving?",
        "Answer": "ALTERNATOR"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following statements is NOT true regarding solar cookers?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Solar cookers that contain parabolic reflectors can cause fires",
            "X": "Their use is limited by the weather",
            "Y": "They do not reach high enough temperatures to sterilize water",
            "Z": "They use no fuel"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Rank in descending order the coercive force typical for the following three materials:  1) pure iron; 2) rare earth magnet; 3) hard steel.",
        "Answer": "RARE EARTH MAGNET, HARD STEEL, PURE IRON"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Converting a power generating plant from coal to natural gas will reduce sulfur emissions by approximately which of the following percentages?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "20%",
            "X": "50%",
            "Y": "70%",
            "Z": "90%"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Identify all of the following four compounds that can be metabolized by humans to produce ATP:  1) maltose; 2) cellobiose [sel-oh-BY-ohs]; 3) glutamine [GLOO-tuh-meen]; 4) palmitate [PAL-mi-tayt].",
        "Answer": "1, 3 AND 4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "How much energy in tons of coal equivalent can be released by using deuterium in 50 cups of sea water in a deuterium \u0152 tritium fusion reactor?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "2",
            "X": "200",
            "Y": "2,000",
            "Z": "2,000,000"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Fluorescence can be understood as the emission of a photon as a molecule transitions from a singlet excited state to a singlet ground state. What phenomenon is understood as a molecule transitioning from a triplet excited state to a singlet ground state and generally takes place on a much longer time scale than fluorescence?",
        "Answer": "PHOSPHORESCENCE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "According to the U.S. Energy Information Administration, energy consumption per capita in the U.S. is expected to change at what annual percentage from now until 2035?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "-0.12",
            "X": "-0.5",
            "Y": "+0.5",
            "Z": "+0.12"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What crystalline solid consists of a methane molecule surrounded by a cage of interlocking water molecules and is typically found on sea floors and under permafrost?",
        "Answer": "METHANE HYDRATE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Most companies pursuing algae as a source of biofuels are pumping nutrient-laden water through plastic or borosilicate glass tubes that are exposed to sunlight. What is the name of the device being used in this algae fuel production process?",
        "Answer": "BIOREACTOR"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT true regarding catalysis?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Biological catalysts are called enzymes",
            "X": "Catalysts lower the activation energy of chemical reactions",
            "Y": "A catalyzed reaction always has the same transition state as the uncatalyzed reaction",
            "Z": "Catalysts have no effect on the equilibrium constant"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Indicate, by number, all of the following statements that must be true for an object to be in static equilibrium [ee-kwuh-LIB-ree-uhm]: 1) All forces are balanced; 2) All torques are balanced; 3) Their pressures are the same.",
        "Answer": "1 AND 2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The buildup of heavier elements in the nuclear fusion processes in stars is limited to elements below what isotope?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Iron-56",
            "X": "Iron-58",
            "Y": "Nickel-62",
            "Z": "Lead-82"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In the U.S., ethanol is produced by a fermentation process involving corn. What is the cool season legume that can be used to produce biodiesel?",
        "Answer": "SOYBEANS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Rank the following light bulb types in terms of luminous efficiency (that is, watts required to generate the same amount of lumens), from MOST efficient to LEAST efficient: incandescent, compact fluorescent, halogen, LED.",
        "Answer": "LED, COMPACT FLUORESCENT, HALOGEN, INCANDESCENT"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Catalysts do not get consumed in reactions; however, platinum in hydrogen fuel cells can become inactive when poisoned by which of the following compounds?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Nitrogen",
            "X": "Hydrogen",
            "Y": "Hydrogen peroxide",
            "Z": "Carbon monoxide"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following statements is false about photovoltaic cells?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "N-type silicon is doped with phosphorus",
            "X": "Phosphorus gives the silicon a positive character, and the tendency to attract electrons",
            "Y": "P-type silicon is doped with boron",
            "Z": "Boron gives the silicon a positive character, and the tendency to attract electrons"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What major rock type is the medium for fracking?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Schist [SHIST]",
            "X": "Shale",
            "Y": "Basalt",
            "Z": "Limestone"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What substance was the primary fuel source for NASA space shuttles?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Propane",
            "X": "Helium gas",
            "Y": "Liquid hydrogen",
            "Z": "Methane"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A 100 mile 765 kilovolt line carrying 1000 megawatts of energy can have losses ranging from 1.1% to 0.5%. Which of the following best approximates the losses as a ratio to the 1.0% of a 345 kilovolt line carrying the same load across the same distance?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1/10",
            "X": "1/4",
            "Y": "4/1",
            "Z": "10/1"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If a single electric distribution line has a resistance of 1 ohm per 1000 meters and current at 50 amps, what will be the voltage reduction over a 10 kilometer run?",
        "Answer": "500"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Energy radiates from a surface as a function of temperature to what power?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1",
            "X": "3",
            "Y": "2",
            "Z": "4"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following rare earth elements is used to produce magnets for wind turbines?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Europium",
            "X": "Gadolinium [gad-l-IN-ee-uhm]",
            "Y": "Scandium",
            "Z": "Neodymium"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What form of petroleum deposit, abundant in Canada and Venezuela, contains naturally occurring mixtures of sand, clay, water, and a dense and extremely viscous form of petroleum?",
        "Answer": "OIL SANDS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "According to a study at Argonne National Laboratories, what is the net energy gain or loss, expressed as a ratio, from producing a gallon of ethanol from corn?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "-0.95",
            "X": "+ 1.0",
            "Y": "+1.1",
            "Z": "+1.3"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following elements is part of the cladding and used as a corrosion-resistant alloy to coat pellets of uranium dioxide prior to fuel rod production?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Cadmium",
            "X": "Zirconium",
            "Y": "Titanium",
            "Z": "Silver"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Indicate all of the following three statements that are true of biodiesel: 1) Biodiesel has better lubricating properties and much higher cetane [SEE-tayn] ratings than today's lower sulfur diesel fuels; 2) Animal fats, algae, and soybean oil are all used to produce biofuels; 3) A biodiesel blend with 80% petroleum diesel is labeled B80.",
        "Answer": "1 AND 2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following types of fuel cell is most commonly used in vehicles?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Alkaline",
            "X": "Polymer electrolyte membrane",
            "Y": "Solid oxide",
            "Z": "Phosphoric acid"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Compounds such as luminol and luciferin demonstrate what property upon oxidation, which can be understood as a ground state reactant becoming a singlet excited product, which then emits a photon as it transitions back to the ground state?",
        "Answer": "CHEMILUMINESCENCE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT an oil product?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Gasoline",
            "X": "Syngas",
            "Y": "Kerosene",
            "Z": "Asphalt"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The battery in your laptop is 4 volts and has a resistance of 10 ohms. In amp-hours, if your laptop charges to 100 percent in an 8 hour workday, what is the initial capacity, assuming perfect efficiency?",
        "Answer": "3.2 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What type of device is used to quantitatively measure the heat released by chemical reactions and physical changes at constant volume?",
        "Answer": "BOMB CALORIMETER"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is closest to the correct global warming potential factor for nitrous oxide (N2O)?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "3",
            "X": "30",
            "Y": "100",
            "Z": "300"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Graphite is a fantastic electrical conductor. What is its crystal structure?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Tetragonal",
            "X": "Planar",
            "Y": "Octahedral",
            "Z": "Buckeyballs"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer:",
        "Question": "What principle of spectroscopy states that electronic transitions generally happen faster than the vibrational timescale and, by extension, that electronic transitions will only occur if the vibrational wave functions of the two states overlap significantly?",
        "Answer": "FRANCK-CONDON PRINCIPLE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT a role that large-scale batteries could play in a power generation portfolio based on renewable energy sources?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Frequency modulation",
            "X": "Peak shaving",
            "Y": "Load leveling",
            "Z": "Voltage modulation"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What term describes quantities that are independent of a system\u2122s path, such as enthalpy and entropy?",
        "Answer": "STATE FUNCTIONS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following compounds acts as a catalyst in the production of biodiesel from oils?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Vegetable oil",
            "X": "Lye",
            "Y": "Methanol",
            "Z": "Copper"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What quantum mechanical approximation states that nuclei move much more slowly than electrons, and thus can be neglected in the molecular Hamiltonian?",
        "Answer": "BORN-OPPENHEIMER APPROXIMATION _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Power companies estimate the over-time cost of designing, building, operating, and decommissioning a power plant in order to calculate which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Intrinsic cost",
            "X": "Comprehensive fuel cost",
            "Y": "Levelized cost",
            "Z": "Future-versus-present earnings"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Identify all of the following three changes that would increase the half-life of a first order reaction: 1) increasing the starting concentration; 2) decreasing the starting concentration; 3) increasing the rate constant.",
        "Answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following processes is used to produce additional ATP for the light-independent reactions of photosynthesis?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Cyclic electron flow",
            "X": "Lactic acid fermentation",
            "Y": "Glycolysis [gly-KOL-uh-sis]",
            "Z": "Beta oxidation"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Assume we have two inlets to a hydroelectric plant\u2122s turbines: one inlet is at 50 m depth, and the second inlet is at 80 m depth. How much greater, by percentage, is the pressure at the deeper compared to the shallower one?",
        "Answer": "60% GREATER"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The presence of what class of compounds in nuclear reactors slows down the neutrons in the core, preventing the development of a potential nuclear bomb?",
        "Answer": "MODERATORS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What extremely powerful biological oxidizing agent is used in photosynthesis to oxidize water and is named for its absorption maximum in the red part of the visible spectrum?",
        "Answer": "P680"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Named after its inventor, what battery powered the earliest telegraphs?",
        "Answer": "DANIELL CELL"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What valuable co-product of the water-gas-shift reaction is left when the resultant CO2 [C \u0152O- two] is removed?",
        "Answer": "HYDROGEN _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following countries has the highest percentage of its electricity production from geothermal energy?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "United States",
            "X": "Philippines",
            "Y": "Greenland",
            "Z": "Iceland"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Order the following four sources of energy from least to greatest in terms of the percentage share of total electricity generation in the United States:  1) coal;  2) nuclear; 3) petroleum; 4) hydropower.",
        "Answer": "3, 4, 2, 1"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following values refers to the maximum amount of non-expansion work that can be extracted from a closed system?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Enthalpy",
            "X": "Entropy",
            "Y": "Helmholtz free energy",
            "Z": "Gibbs free energy"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The addition of 2.0 moles of sulfur dioxide to 1.0 mole of diatomic oxygen forms 2.0 moles of sulfur trioxide at a constant pressure and releases 198 kilojoules of energy as heat. In kilojoules, what is the change in enthalpy for this reaction?",
        "Answer": "-198"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Since 2007 all cars and trucks in the US have been produced to be able to use what specific ethanol fuel blend?",
        "Answer": "E15"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the term used to describe the medium in nuclear reactors that is used to reduce the speed of fast neutrons?",
        "Answer": "MODERATOR"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Aside from any impurities, what is the co-product resulting from biodiesel production that is produced in far greater quantities than it is currently used?",
        "Answer": "GLYCERIN"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following regions of the United States has the greatest amount of installed wind power capacity?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "West coast",
            "X": "Midwest",
            "Y": "New England",
            "Z": "Southeast"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Most renewable electricity generation worldwide is generated by what form of renewable energy?",
        "Answer": "HYDROELECTRICITY"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following elements has the largest 2nd ionization energy?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Boron",
            "X": "Oxygen",
            "Y": "Sodium",
            "Z": "Lithium"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "As anthropogenic greenhouse gas emissions, specifically carbon dioxide, accumulate in the atmosphere, what is anticipated to happen to ocean pH and temperature?",
        "Answer": "OCEAN pH WILL DECREASE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In the Northern Hemisphere, to minimize direct summer sunlight from entering a home through its windows, in what direction should most windows be facing?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "North",
            "X": "East",
            "Y": "South",
            "Z": "West"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In most climates, which of the following is a concern with heat pump hot water heater technology?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Water temperature",
            "X": "Tank size",
            "Y": "Cold air exhaust",
            "Z": "Energy consumption"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What equation of electrochemistry can be used to determine the equilibrium reduction potential based on the standard reduction potential, temperature, activity, and reaction quotient?",
        "Answer": "NERNST EQUATION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following electricity generation methods has low fixed cost and high operating cost?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Wind",
            "X": "Natural gas",
            "Y": "Solar",
            "Z": "Hydroelectric"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In comparison to a gallon of gasoline, how much energy is contained in a gallon of ethanol?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "70%",
            "X": "90%",
            "Y": "110%",
            "Z": "120%"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the secondary voltage, in volts, in a transformer with a primary current of 50 amps, a secondary current of 100 amps, and a 110-volt primary voltage?",
        "Answer": "55 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "As the battery capacity decreases how does the rate of discharge change?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Increases",
            "X": "Decreases",
            "Y": "Stays the same",
            "Z": "Depends on brand"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What process in plant cells is primarily responsible for storing energy from ATP and NADPH [A- T-P and N-A-D-P-H] by synthesizing sugars?",
        "Answer": "CALVIN CYCLE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Lighting products often come with a rating that reflects the temperature of an ideal black body if it were to emit the same hue as that of the lighting product. What is this rating known as?",
        "Answer": "COLOR TEMPERATURE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following countries has the highest percentage of its electricity produced by nuclear power?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Japan",
            "X": "France",
            "Y": "United States",
            "Z": "Russia"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Natural gas systems are the greatest source of U.S. anthropogenic [an-thruh-puh-JEN-ik] methane emissions. What metabolic process, occurring in the rumens of domesticated animals, results in the second-greatest source of methane emissions?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Photosynthesis",
            "X": "Lactation",
            "Y": "Fermentation",
            "Z": "The Krebs cycle"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Which U.S. government body regulates nuclear power production in this country?",
        "Answer": "U. S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The Clean Air Act Amendments established rules on a variety of pollutants. Since 1990, by what approximate amount have ambient sulfate concentrations decreased in most regions of the U.S.?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "10%",
            "X": "25%",
            "Y": "50%",
            "Z": "90%"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Consider 1.0 moles of an ideal gas undergoing isobaric expansion from 273 to 373 Kelvin. Assuming that the ideal gas constant is 8.314 Joules per mole kelvin, how much work, in joules to the nearest tenth, is done by the gas?",
        "Answer": "831.4  _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following foods has the highest energy density?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Lean meat of a rabbit",
            "X": "Cell wall of celery",
            "Y": "Pericarp of an apple",
            "Z": "Butter churned from milk"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Consider a Carnot engine operating between two reservoirs [REZ-er-vwahrs] of different temperatures. If the temperatures in Kelvin of both reservoirs are doubled, by what factor is the efficiency multiplied?",
        "Answer": "ONE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In a solar power tower system, what are the names of the mirrors that focus sunlight onto a pipe located at the focal line, heating up fluid inside and producing steam that drives a turbine?",
        "Answer": "PARABOLIC TROUGH"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Carnot efficiency is limited by what physical quantity?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Pressure",
            "X": "Entropy",
            "Y": "Flow rate",
            "Z": "Temperature"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What type of biofuel is produced by the anaerobic digestion or fermentation of biodegradable materials, primarily producing methane and carbon dioxide?",
        "Answer": "BIOGAS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Assuming that one maintained a calorie deficit of 500 calories per day, approximately how long would it take to burn one pound of fat?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1 day",
            "X": "1 week",
            "Y": "1 month",
            "Z": "1 year"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What is permeability as it applies to magnetic materials?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Degree of magnetization that a material obtains in response to an applied magnetic field",
            "X": "Ability of a magnetic material to move gases through the material",
            "Y": "Amount of magnetic field needed to be applied to saturate the material",
            "Z": "Ability of a magnetic material to pass a current"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What would be the total kinetic energy of an object rolling down a ramp with no slippage?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "\u00bd MV2 [half M-V squared]",
            "X": "\u00bd I omega2 [half I omega squared]",
            "Y": "\u00bd MV2 + \u00bd I omega2 [half M-V- squared plus half I omega squared]",
            "Z": "0"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What general type of nuclear reactor generates more fissile [FIS-uhl] material than it consumes?",
        "Answer": "BREEDER REACTOR"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is an isotope that has attracted recent interest in terms of developing a new generation of cleaner, proliferation-resistant nuclear power?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Uranium-235",
            "X": "Thorium-232",
            "Y": "Plutonium-239",
            "Z": "Uranium-238"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the efficiency of a Carnot engine transferring heat from a reservoir at 500 Kelvin to a cold reservoir at 200 Kelvin?",
        "Answer": "60%"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In general, there are three types of compensation agreements for electricity generated using distributed generation, such as solar photovoltaic. All of the following are examples, except:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Rate allocation",
            "X": "Feed-in Tariff (FIT)",
            "Y": "Net metering",
            "Z": "Power purchase agreement"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "ENERGY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Quartz clocks use a crystal oscillator that generates regularly timed electric pulses to keep track of time. What is the name of the effect through which crystals such as quartz can accumulate electric charges?",
        "Answer": "PIEZOELECTRICITY"
    }
]